[{"answer": "The outcome still isn't clear.", "docId": "110315pmt", "aSentId": 113, "question": "Is it as dangerous as it seems?", "qSentId": 112}, {"answer": "They have no need to keep more people around than they absolutely need since all of them are soaking up dose.", "docId": "110315pmt", "aSentId": 132, "question": "Are there enough people physically to do the job that's required?", "qSentId": 131}, {"answer": "In Chernobyl, a completely different kind of reactor.", "docId": "110315pmt", "aSentId": 138, "question": "How does this disaster compare -- this nuclear plant to something like Chernobyl?", "qSentId": 137}, {"answer": "Probably that the spent fuel spool is on fire because what would burn there is the metal cladding, and that's very difficult to put out.", "docId": "110315pmt", "aSentId": 163, "question": "Without wanting to be doom-laden about this, but what is the worst possible news that you would hear as an expert in this area from that plant?", "qSentId": 162}, {"answer": "Well, the main thing I've said, Piers, is not that, but it's simply that it's way too early to know.", "docId": "110315pmt", "aSentId": 172, "question": "Why are you confident this is the right way to go?", "qSentId": 171}, {"answer": "Sure.", "docId": "110315pmt", "aSentId": 182, "question": "We've got lots of reactors, many by the sea?", "qSentId": 181}, {"answer": "Piers, it's an obvious question.", "docId": "110315pmt", "aSentId": 184, "question": "What's going to happen if the same thing happens here?", "qSentId": 183}, {"answer": "Yes.", "docId": "110315pmt", "aSentId": 194, "question": "Quite clearly, this is an ongoing, very serious and dangerous situation, isn't it?", "qSentId": 193}, {"answer": "Piers, I have no earthly idea.", "docId": "110315pmt", "aSentId": 199, "question": "What are the lessons that we should learn from what's happened in regard to America's plants, do you think?", "qSentId": 198}, {"answer": "I think it would -- I think it would be irresponsible to do otherwise.", "docId": "110315pmt", "aSentId": 211, "question": "Isn't that the point?", "qSentId": 210}, {"answer": "Well, Piers, I fully agree that there are important lessons to be learned by -- from what has happened at Fukushima.", "docId": "110315pmt", "aSentId": 235, "question": "Today the energy secretary, Stephen Chu, said that U.S. reactors are designed to withstand hurricanes and tsunamis, but given geologists' maximum predictions, is that actually enough?", "qSentId": 234}, {"answer": "Well, let's remember that the reactors in Japan were quite old.", "docId": "110315pmt", "aSentId": 241, "question": "As things stand given your knowledge of the nuclear power plants in America, how many of them would you think are able to withstands an earthquake of a magnitude we saw in Japan?", "qSentId": 240}, {"answer": "Well, the problem with that is that you'd end up building a reactor in a zone that is not subject to earthquakes to withstand an enormous earthquake.", "docId": "110315pmt", "aSentId": 249, "question": "Wouldn't that be the first point of thumb that you'd choose?", "qSentId": 248}, {"answer": "I do, but Piers, lets me make a point.", "docId": "110315pmt", "aSentId": 261, "question": "Finally, Ambassador Ritch, do you think we're getting the truth out of the Japanese authorities?", "qSentId": 260}, {"answer": "The experience is just horrifying because you feel so powerless with the amount of power of the water.", "docId": "110315pmt", "aSentId": 299, "question": "For people like most of us who've never been anywhere near a tsunami, what is the experience like when it happens?", "qSentId": 298}, {"answer": "On the level of helping children, the best way for them to recover and start healing process is to go back to normalcy, to go back to school, which is safe.", "docId": "110315pmt", "aSentId": 328, "question": "What is the most effective thing that Americans can do to help?", "qSentId": 327}, {"answer": "You always will keep it inside.", "docId": "110315pmt", "aSentId": 338, "question": "Do you still have nightmares about it now?", "qSentId": 337}, {"answer": "The message for them is that my heart is breaking looking at what they are going through.", "docId": "110315pmt", "aSentId": 348, "question": "And finally, what would your message be to the people of Japan who are suffering so badly at the moment?", "qSentId": 347}, {"answer": "With time, Piers.", "docId": "110315pmt", "aSentId": 370, "question": "How are they going to bounce back?", "qSentId": 369}, {"answer": "Think of it in terms of they are producing and consuming less as a society.", "docId": "110315pmt", "aSentId": 384, "question": "What will that mean for prices, in terms of their exports going forward?", "qSentId": 383}, {"answer": "It's going to be helpful at the margin.", "docId": "110315pmt", "aSentId": 397, "question": "Is that going to be helpful to Japan, do you think?", "qSentId": 396}, {"answer": "Well, I think that we in America -- when we come across a crisis, we tend to come apart at the seams.", "docId": "110315pmt", "aSentId": 412, "question": "What is it about the Japanese people that allows them to deal with such catastrophe in what appears to be such a remarkably calm manner?", "qSentId": 411}, {"answer": "In general, Japanese officials leave one with kind of a sense of horror, I mean, just a difficult grappling with crisis.", "docId": "110315pmt", "aSentId": 422, "question": "Are they very pro-active at getting things back on their feet again?", "qSentId": 421}, {"answer": "Yes, absolutely.", "docId": "110315pmt", "aSentId": 440, "question": "Is that part of their psyche, as well?", "qSentId": 439}, {"answer": "Oh, of course.", "docId": "110315pmt", "aSentId": 449, "question": "Do you still have friends over there?", "qSentId": 448}, {"answer": "Right, there are four different types of radiation, Piers.", "docId": "110315pmt", "aSentId": 471, "question": "Can you talk me through the relative toxicity of each of these?", "qSentId": 470}, {"answer": "We've been hearing that the levels of radiation are not quite at the level that you would see in order to have acute radiation sickness.", "docId": "110315pmt", "aSentId": 478, "question": "What is the understanding of the levels of radiation coming out of this Japanese plant?", "qSentId": 477}, {"answer": "Right, it's interesting.", "docId": "110315pmt", "aSentId": 493, "question": "Tell me this, if they are exposed to very high dosages of radiation, what physically happens to a human being when that happens to them?", "qSentId": 492}, {"answer": "That's right.", "docId": "110315pmt", "aSentId": 527, "question": "And what are you hearing from Bahrain, where there seems to be an escalation in violence there, as well?", "qSentId": 526}]